Preliminary Guide to the Stanley Hauerwas Papers, 1962-2018 and undated RL.00519
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Stanley Hauerwas papers
1962-2018 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hauerwas, Stanley, 1940-
RL.00519
106.75 Linear Feet
Stanley Hauerwas is a Duke Divinity School professor. Collection contains personal and professional materials documenting Hauerwas's career as an ethicist, professor, and scholar at the Duke University Divinity School and School of Law. Includes correspondence, lectures, professional engagement files, committee work, drafts, publications, and other assorted materials. Collection is closed pending processing.
Access Restrictions
Collection is closed pending processing because it contains various materials restricted by the donor, University Archives policy, and FERPA law.
Provenance
Collection received as a gift from Stanley Hauerwas in 1995-2008, 2018.
Biographical Note
Missing Title
1940 Born
1965 B.A. Southwestern University B.D. Yale University
1968 Ph.D.. Yale University
1970-1984 Assistant Professor and Professor Notre Dame University
1985-present Professor at Duke University
Stanley Hauerwas is the Gilbert T. Rowe Professor of Theological Ethics in the Duke Divinity School as well as Professor in the Duke School of Law. He came to Duke in 1984 after serving on the faculties of the University of Notre Dame and Augustana College. He has published ten books and many articles dealing with a variety of topics, many of them interdisciplinary, centering on moral discourse within the contemporary Christian community. Two recent books are A Better Hope: Resources for a Church Confronting Capitalism, Democracy, and Postmodernity (2000) and Dispatches from the Front: Theological Engagements with the Secular (1994). His work is typically non-denominational and often provocative and controversial. Hauerwas was named America's Best Theologian by TIME Magazine in 2001, and was the first American in 40 years to deliver the Gifford Lectureship at St. Andrew's College, also in 2001.
Collection Overview
Letters to Hauerwas (28,403 items, 52.25 linear feet; dated 1972-2000) from Paul Ramsey discussing points of theology and Christian ethics; correspondence, addresses and writings, clippings, and notes relating to Hauerwas's work as a Christian ethicist; a copy of Ramsey's work Speak Up for Just War or Pacifism that contains an epilogue by Hauerwas, and Ramsey's letters to Hauerwas regarding the completion of the book; other papers on the ethical questions surrounding the issue of Christianity and war; 19 essays on Ramsey by various authors; and subject files focusing on conferences, workshops, topical subject areas, and writings and speeches by Hauerwas and others. There is also correspondence regarding the work of students and colleagues; university committees; events; publications; reviews of Dispatches from the Front; and miscellaneous materials. Container lists exist for a portion of this material. (88-017, 89-035, 95-111, 98-419, 99-003, 00-296, 00-333)
The addition to the collection (2001-0138) (939 items, 1.5 linear feet; dated 1991-1999) includes professional correspondence and recommendations for graduate students he mentored; drafts and finished essays by Hauerwas, his colleagues, graduate students, and those published in The Hauerwas Reader (Duke University Press, 2001); and materials relating to Hauerwas' conference attendance (ca. 1991-1999). There are also 39 electronic documents originally on three 3.5" diskettes and migrated to the electronic records server. A container list was not created for this accession.
The addition to the collection (2001-0181)(2175 items, 3.4 linear feet; dated 1993-1999) comprises primarily incoming and copies of outgoing correspondence with students, former students, and colleagues, including drafts of essays. Also includes material on conferences Hauerwas attended.
The addition (2002-0236) (3325 items, 5.2 linear feet; dated 1962-2002) is comprised of Hauerwas' lectures and course materials, professional correspondence, printed material, and reviews of his publications. Also includes his graduate student and event files.
The addition (2003-0116) (2175 items, 3.4 linear feet; dated 1990-2003) is chiefly comprised of incoming professional correspondence, including commentary on the religious aspects of the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001; also includes recommendations written by Hauerwas; drafts and finished essays by Hauerwas and others; and correspondence, essays, and other materials relating to conferences Hauerwas attended.
The addition (2003-0144) (3150 items, 5.0 linear feet; dated 1992-2003) contains mainly essays received by or written by Hauerwas; as well as incoming and outgoing correspondence with former students, colleagues and others.
Additions (2007-082 and 2007-083)(2100 items, 2.8 lin. ft.; dated 1991-2003) contains files related to former students and colleagues, as well as information about conferences. The files primarily include correspondence, drafts of essays, doctoral exams, and recommendations.
The addition (2008-0123) (13500 items; 19 lin. ft.; dated 1995-2005) contains subject files, correspondence and other professional files collected while Sarah Freedman was Hauerwas' assistant.
Addition (2009-0094) (2 items; 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 2006 and no date) contains two DVDs with programs by Hauerwas: the inaugural Will D. Campbell lecture series on Faith and Social Justices (2006) and Why Religious Diversity is a Bad Idea, from the Chicago Sunday Evening Club.
Additions (2009-0272 and 2009-0273) (7200 items; 9.6 lin. ft.; dated 2001-2008) include travel materials, research and writings, and coursework and student correspondence from 2002-2006. Also includes reactions and press from Hauerwas's Time Magazine award (2001) and a manuscript of his book 'Hannah's Child' (summer 2008).
Addition (2012-0039) (3.0 lin. ft.) contains speaking/travel files, student files, correspondence, and writings. Arranged alphabetically within sub-series.
Addition (2012-0108) (3.0 lin. ft.; dated 1990-2001) contains Hauerwas's writing files, including some editorial correspondence and notes, arranged alphabetically by title.
Addition (2019-0074) (6.2 lin. ft.; dated 1981-2018) contains primarily travel and lecture files, along with reviews, biographical information, correspondence, research files, and contracts.
Machine-readable records; Christian ethics; Christian ethics -- Study and teaching; Theologians -- United States -- Correspondence; War -- Religious aspects -- Christianity; Duke University -- Faculty; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 -- Religious aspects; Ramsey, Paul; Hauerwas, Stanley, 1940-. Correspondence; Hauerwas, Stanley, 1940-; Duke University. Divinity School
- Accession 95-111
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Jan. 1977 - Dec. 1984. (Box 1)
    - Jan. 1985- Oct. 1986. (Box 2)
    - Oct. 1986- Dec. 1987 (Box 3)
    - Jan. 1988- Dec. 1988 (Box 4)
    - Jan. 1989- Mar. 1990 (Box 5)
    - Mar. 1990- Dec. 1990. (Box 6)
    - Jan. 1991- Dec. 1991. (Box 7)
    - Jan. 1992- Oct. 1992. (Box 8)
    - Nov. 1992- July 1993. (Box 9)
    - Aug. 1993- Jan. 1994. (Box 10)
  - Invitations (Box 10)
  - Travel Expenses (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Duke faculty position for which Hauerwas was hired (Box 10)
  - Manuscripts received (Box 11)
    - A-G. (Box 11)
    - G-M. (Box 12)
    - M-V. (Box 13)
    - W (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous letters and manuscripts (Box 14)
  - Subject Files (Box 15-23)
    Scope and Contents note
    The Subject Files contain materials relating to subject areas, writings and speeches, and conference or educational events. Each subject file container is arranged in internal alphabetical order by topics, personal names, or institutions.
- Accession 2000-0296
  - Files Regarding Various Persons
    - Heide, Gale (Box 1)
    - Heymans, Steve (Box 1)
    - Barns, Ian (Box 1)
    - Bartley, Michael R. (Box 1)
    - Bryant, Robt. (Box 1)
    - Byrne, Julie (Box 1)
    - Kings College, Canada-Trokcak, Ron (Box 1)
    - Lind, Marcia (Box 1)
    - Campbell, Dean Dennis (Box 1)
    - Fagar, Charles (Box 1)
    - Fekete, David (Box 1)
    - Cowlings, Neil (Box 1)
    - Gaita, Raimond (Box 1)
    - Breeneman, James (Box 1)
  - Files Regarding Academic, Committees, et al.
    - Provost and Distinguished Professors (Box 1)
    - APT-Student Evaluations (Box 1)
    - Appointments, Promotion, and Tenure (Box 1)
    - Davidson Group on Arts and Humanities (Box 1)
    - American Theological Society (Box 1)
    - Between Times Stuff (Box 1)
    - Dean Search Committee (Box 1)
    - Faculty Planning and Appointments Committee (Box 1)
    - Duke University Press (Box 1)
    - Fiscal-Stan (Box 1)
    - Center for Ethical and Political Theory-Gillespie and Flanagan (Box 1)
    - Chaplains in the Military (Box 1)
    - Editorial Advisory Board (Box 1)
    - Con't Ed and Lectures Committee (Box 1)
    - Greenwall Foundation RFP Fellowship Program in Health Policy and Bioethics (Box 1)
    - Graduate Program-Our Religion Dept. (Box 1)
    - Chafe Review (Box 1)
    - Incompletes (Box 1)
    - Advisors (Box 1)
  - Files Regarding Events, Lectures
    - Illinois College- 1994 Oct. 26 (Box 1)
    - Cultural Christianity (Box 1)
    - Alzheimer's: The Theological Disease (Box 1)
    - Hauerwas Colloquium on the Law-Notre Dame, IN- 1994 Jan. 30-31 (Box 1)
    - Murdoch Conference-University of Chicago- 1994 May 11-13 (Box 1)
    - New Testament and Ethics Conference-Richard Hayes-Duke University- 1995 Mar. 30-Apr. 1 (Box 1)
    - Neibur Lectures, Elmhurst College- 1995 Apr. (Box 1)
    - Bioethics Meeting-Duke and UNC-Monthly (Box 1)
    - Gospel and Our Culture Network-Atlanta, GA- 1995 Feb. 20 (Box 1)
  - Files Regarding Written Works: Published and Unpublished
    - For Christ's Sake: The Independent (Box 1)
    - In Good Company- Reviews (Box 1)
    - In Good Company-Acknowledgments (Box 1)
    - Dispatches from the Front (Duke University Press)-Review File, Folder 1 of 2 (Box 1)
    - Dispatches from the Front (Duke University Press)-Review File, Folder 2 of 2 (Box 2)
    - But Was It Just- Reviews (Box 2)
    - Doctrine: Relations of Doctrine and Ethics (Cambridge Press)-Companions (Box 2)
    - In Good Company-Contract (Box 2)
    - In Good Company-Rights and Permission (Box 2)
    - The Church with the Soul of a Nation-Review of George Mardsen's Book (Box 2)
    - Canon, Critique, and Constitution by Dennis O'Brien (Box 2)
    - Democracy Prospers with Nationalism by George Wills (Durham Herald Sun) (Box 2)
    - Christian Bioethics Subscriptions (Box 2)
    - Christian Existence Today by Stanley Hauerwas (Box 2)
    - Chronicle-Letter (Box 2)
    - The Pope Pits Theology Back into Moral Theology- Commonweal (Box 2)
    - Culture Wars: A Response- Soundings (Box 2)
    - Gustafson Festschrift (Box 2)
    - Greenway Response for Koinonia (Box 3)
    - McInerny Festschrift (Box 3)
    - Mennonites on Hauerwas (Box 3)
    - Milbank-Jensen (Box 3)
    - Naming the Silences- Reviews (Box 3)
    - Against the Nation-Reviews (Box 3)
    - Peaceable Kingdom (Box 3)
- Accession 2000-0333
  - Files on individual students and colleagues, 38 files (Box 1-2)
    Includes correspondence, writings, and miscellaneous materials. Names include Tommy Langford and Desmond Tutu.
  - Correspondence (primarily outgoing), 1995 March-1998 December, 54 files (Box 2-3)
  - Files regarding publications, 13 files (Box 3-4)
  - Committee and Department files, 4 files (Box 4)
  - Files regarding Trips to Events, 61 files (Box 4-5)
  - Writings, 25 folders (Box 5-6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Accession 2001-0181
  Conditions Governing Access note
  This accession contains sensitive information. Patrons must sign a release form before using the material in this accession.
  - Correspondence, 1993-1999 (Box 1)
    - Miroslav Volf (Box 1)
    - Brent Walters, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Sondra Wheeler (Box 1)
      Attention: Contains sensitive information.
    - Bob Wells, DUMC Communications (Box 1)
    - George Wiegal (Box 1)
    - Micheal Walzer (Box 1)
    - David Yeago, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Rowan Williams (Box 1)
    - Catherine Miles Wallace, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and Conferences Attended (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1999
      - Catherine Miles Wallace (Box 2)
      - Kate Wallace II, 3 Folders (Box 2)
      - Rusty Reno, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Conferences Attended, 1998 (Box 2)
      Includes: Social Bioethics, Contemporary Religious Thought, Genetics, Intervarsity, Metheseco, Bluffton.
  - Conferences Attended and Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Conferences Attended, 1998 (Box 3)
      Includes: Sin Death Devil (Minn), Berkman Class (D.C.), Good Shepard Families (Bronxville), University of Richmond, Thomas Moore College, Oglethorpe University (Atlanta), University of Pacific (CA), Society of Christian Ethics.
    - Correspondence, 1994-1999
      - Theology Division (Box 3)
      - Richard Steele (Box 3)
      - Joel Shuman, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Gary Petrillo (Box 3)
      - Keith Pavlischek (Box 3)
      - Al Neiman (Box 3)
      - James Lewis (Box 3)
      - John Milbank (Box 3)
      - Debra Dean Murphy (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1999 (Box 4)
    - Modern Theology (Box 4)
    - Martha Nussbaum (Box 4)
    - Ken Craycraft, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Center For Study Of Applied Ethics (Box 4)
    - Lloyd Bailey (Box 4)
    - Duke Admissions Committee, Dept. Of Religion (Box 4)
    - Scott Davis and Richmond Warcraft, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Scott Davis, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence and Financial Sheets (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1999
      - Hutter Reinhard (Box 5)
      - Bruce Kaye, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Alan Johnson (Box 5)
    - Financial Sheets, 2 folders (Box 5)
      Includes: Grants, Balance Sheets.
    - Correspondence, 1994-1999
      - Pew Evangelical Scholars (Box 5)
      - Richard Miller (Box 5)
      - Curtis Freeman, 2 of 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 6)
    - Curtis Freeman, 3rd of 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Sam Fleischacker (Box 6)
    - Micheal Gillespie (Box 6)
    - Tom Harvey (Box 6)
    - Dan Hardy (Box 6)
    - Thomas Heilke (Box 6)
    - Gail Hamner (Box 6)
- Accession 2002-0236
  Contains sensitive material (personal health information, recommendations, student files). Patrons must sign a waiver concerning privacy rights. Contact Research Services staff.
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1999
      - Travis Kroeber (Box 1)
      - David Aers (Box 1)
      - Jones, Logan (Box 1)
      - Kyle Childers (Box 1)
      - James Burtchaell (Box 1)
      - David Burrell (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    [Contains sensitive information (personal health information, recommendations, student files). Patrons must sign a waiver concerning privacy rights. Contact Research Services.]
    - Correspondence, 1988-2001
      - Arne Rasmusson (Box 2)
      - Michael Quirk (Box 2)
      - John Berkman (Box 2)
      - Fritz Bauerschmidt (Box 2)
      - Michael Baxter (Box 2)
    - Graduate student files, 1988-1997 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    [Contains sensitive information (student files). Patrons must sign a waiver concerning privacy rights. Contact Research Services.]
    - Correspondence/graduate student files, 1994-2002
      - David Cloutier (Box 3)
      - Treci Lysaught (Box 3)
    - Event files, 1999 (conferences, presentations, etc.) (Box 3)
    - Printed material, 1971-1998 (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Printed material, 1971-1998 (cont.) (Box 4)
    - Hauerwas publication files (articles, interviews), 1995-1996 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1993
      - Reinhard Hutter (Box 4)
    - Course/seminar information files (syllabi, exams, etc.), 1973-1975, 1996 and undated (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    [Contains sensitive information (student grades). Patrons must sign a waiver concerning privacy rights. Contact Research Services.]
    - Loose material: course reading lists, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Reviews/correspondence files regarding Hauerwas publications, 1980-1985 and undated (Box 5)
    - Course/presentation information files (outlines, grades, etc., largely concerning ethics), 1969-1982 and undated (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    [Contains sensitive information (student grades, papers). Patrons must sign a waiver concerning privacy rights. Contact Research Services.]
    - Course/presentation information files (notes, student papers and grades, largely concerning ethics), 1969-1985 and undated (Box 6)
    - Loose material: course information, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Course/presentation information files (notes, student papers and grades, largely concerning ethics), 1962-1987 and undated (Box 7)
    - Reviews/correspondence files regarding Hauerwas publications, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Subject file, 1985 and undated
      - Professional ethics (Box 7)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Yale Institute information, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Subject files, 1975-1977 and undated
      - Abortion (Box 8)
      - Obscenity (Box 8)
    - Loose material: notes, clippings, articles, journals, course information, 1973-1998 and undated (Box 8)
    - Course/seminar information files, 1998 and undated (Box 8)
    - Loose material: correspondence, drafts of Hauerwas's Prayers Plainly Spoken, 1998 and undated (Box 8)
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Prayers (student writings?), 2001 and undated (Box 9)
    - Reviews of Hauerwas publications files, 1974-1990 and undated (Box 9)
    - Course/seminar information files (notes, syllabi, etc.), 1986-1997 and undated
      - Duke MALS course information (Box 9)
- Accession 2003-0116
  Accession requires screening for third party privacy rights before use.
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 1)
    - Essays written or received by Hauerwas, 1990-2001 (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 2)
    - Essays written or received by Hauerwas, 1990-2001 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, notes, and records regarding lectures and conferences, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, notes and records regarding lectures and conferences, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 3)
    - Essays written or received by Hauerwas, 1990-2001 (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 4)
    - Records regarding lecture in Japan, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Essays written or received by Hauerwas, 1990-2001 (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 5)
    - Essays written or received by Hauerwas, 1990-2001 (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Essays written or received by Hauerwas, 1990-2001 (Box 6)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, including commentary on the religious aspects of the terrorist attacks of 9/11/2001, 2001 (Box 6)
- Accession 2003-0144
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Essays received by Hauerwas, 1994-2001 (Box 1)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1991-2002 (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Essays received by Hauerwas, 1992-1997 (Box 2)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1995-2002 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Essays by Hauerwas and others, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1992-2002 (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Essays received by Hauerwas, 1995-1999 (Box 4)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1995-2001 (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Essays received by Hauerwas, 1996-1999 (Box 5)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1993-1999 (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Essays received by Hauerwas, 1995-2003 (Box 6)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1993-2001 (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Essays received by Hauerwas, 1995-2001 (Box 7)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1996-2001 (Box 7)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Essays received by Hauerwas, 1998-1997 (Box 8)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 8)
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Essays received by Hauerwas, 1996-1998 (Box 9)
    - Incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1995-2001 (Box 9)
- Accession, 2004 (2007-0082), 1 boxes
  Addition (dated 1991-2003) contains files related to former students and colleagues, as well as information about conferences. The files primarily include correspondence, drafts of essays, doctoral exams, and recommendations.
  - Student and colleague files, 1991-2003 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence, recommendations, essays and exams.
    [Contains sensitive materials. Access is restricted.]
    - Bahnson, Fred, 2000-2003 (Box 1)
    - DeVille, Adam, 2000-2003 (Box 1)
    - Ewell, Samuel, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - Hamner, Gail, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
    - Hatchell, Stephanie, 1995-1998 (Box 1)
    - Kenneson, Phil, 1991-1999 (Box 1)
    - Lamadrid, Lucas, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
    - MacSwain, Rob, 1995-2001 (Box 1)
    - Vidu, Adonis, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
- Accession, 2005 (2007-0083), 6 boxes
  - Student, colleague, and subject files, 1994-2003 (Box 1)
    - McCann, John (Box 1)
    - Wyatt, Rev. Lee (Box 1)
    - Woodhead, Linda (Box 1)
    - Haldane, John (Box 1)
    - Ramsey papers (Box 1)
    - Pilgrim Press (Box 1)
    - Abingdon Press (Box 1)
    - Peculiar Books and convocation (Box 1)
    - Ward, Graham (Box 1)
    - Toor, Rachel (Box 1)
    - Bailie, Gil (Box 1)
    - Rudy, Kathy - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Conference file, Eastern Mennonite University, 2003 (Box 2)
  - JRE-Contributing Editor Essay (Box 2)
  - Notre Dame Press files and correspondence (Box 2)
  - Correspondence-Lewis V. Bradley (Box 2)
  - Declined invitations to appear/speak, 1994-1999 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 2)
  - Correspondence-Dale Martin New Beginnings file (Box 2)
  - Student, colleague, and subject files
    - Frank, Arthur (Box 2)
    - Dyson, Michael Eric (Box 2)
    - Thomas, Scott (Box 2)
    - Baker, Andy (Box 2)
  - Student, colleague, and subject files (Box 3)
    - King, Rob (Box 3)
    - MacIntyre, Alastair (Box 3)
    - Willimon, Will (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous files (Box 3)
    - McCulley, Mark (Box 3)
    - Placher, William (Box 3)
    - Springsted, Eric (Box 3)
    - Koonz, Claudia (Box 3)
    - Southwestern University, 1995-1999 (Box 3)
    - Prisoners - Deutsch (Box 3)
    - Wilderness Wanderings: Reviews (Box 3)
    - McKenny, Gerald (Box 3)
  - Student, colleague, and subject files (Box 4)
    - Marsden, George (Box 4)
    - Willimon, Will, 1995-1999 (Box 4)
    - Amato-von Hemert, Katherine (Box 4)
    - Gomez-Palacio, Enrique (Box 4)
    - Law, with Duke Law School - J. Powell, 1996-1999 (Box 4)
    - Lewis, Ted, 2000-2002 (Box 4)
  - Quirk (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 4)
  - Student, colleague, and subject files (Box 5)
    - Reno, Rusty, 2000-2002 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 5)
    - Preller Festschrift (Box 5)
    - Laytham, Brent (Box 5)
    - Faculty Associates (Box 5)
    - Alison, James, 1996-1999 (Box 5)
    - With Wells, An Ethics Companion (Box 5)
  - Student, Colleague, and other files (Box 6)
    - Smith, Moody (Box 6)
    - Pew, Still (Box 6)
    - Vwllenga (Box 6)
    - Durham U., Durham, UK (Box 6)
    - Ellen Davis Review (Box 6)
    - Prof. Charlie Pinches, 1997-1999 (Box 6)
- Accession 2008-0123 and Accession 2009-0094, 12 boxes
  Addition (2008-0123) (13500 items; 19 lin. ft.; dated 1995-2005) contains subject files, correspondence and other professional files collected while Sarah Freedman was Hauerwas' assistant.